鬼庄园
第二季 第１集 "不错的好地方"
北加利福尼亚
伦敦
‎我和我的爱人
We lay my love and I...
‎躺在哭泣的柳树下
beneath the weeping willow.
‎如今只剩我一人‎...
But now alone I lie...
‎躺在柳树旁哭泣
and weep beside the tree.
‎唱着 "哦 伤心的柳树"
Singin', "O willow waly"
‎柳树也跟着我流泪
by the tree that weeps with me.
‎唱着 "哦 伤心的柳树"
Singing, "O willow waly"
‎直到爱人回到我身旁
till my lover return to me.
‎请大家听我说 好吗
Can I have your attention, please?
‎你们马上就要用餐 但是...
You'll get to your meals momentarily, but first...
‎新娘请我先说几句
the bride has asked me to speak.
‎我以为她在开玩笑
I thought she was joking!
‎你为什么要给自己的婚礼
Why invite such catastrophe
‎找这样的麻烦
upon your own wedding?
‎不过她解释说
But, as she explained,
‎"不 才不是呢 不是婚礼
"No, heavens, no. Not the wedding,
‎是练习餐"
the practice meal."
‎拜托 这是预演晚宴
The rehearsal dinner, for God's sakes!
‎身为略有醉意
I must claim my right as a slightly drunk,
时差还没倒过来的英国人
completely jet-lagged Englishman
‎我要声明 我说的都是真心话
to well and truly speak my mind.
‎因为我想提醒你们大家
Because I want to warn you all,
‎你们年轻人完全不知道
you young people have absolutely no idea
‎你们让自己陷入了什么境地
what you are letting yourselves in for.
‎有个可怕的统计数据
Here's a horrifying statistic.
‎你们知道现在几乎有一半的婚姻
Did you know that almost half of marriages these days
‎没有以离婚告终吗
do not end up in divorce?
‎也就是说 你们俩很有可能
That means there's a strong probability that you two
看着对方死去
get to watch each other die.
‎这是人们想要的结果
And that's the preferred outcome.
‎真正爱另一个人
To truly love another person
‎就是要接受 爱之深切
is to accept that the work of loving them
‎失去后痛也值得
is worth the pain of losing them.
‎就是这样
And that's it.
‎仅此而已
That's all.
‎如果你也像我一样害怕
And if that scares you as much as it scares me,
‎那我会说"快跑"
then I say run.
‎跑到巴厘岛的海滩上嗑药吧
Go off and do drugs on a beach in Bali.
‎全身心投入到精神生活中
Devote yourself to a life of the mind. Run!
‎快跑 趁你还能跑
Run while you still can.
你还年轻 你身体强壮 这个世界...
You're young, you're strong. The world...
‎不 我说真的 ‎
No, I'm serious,
-我们其实不愿意住在这里  -她不愿意
- we actually refused to stay here. - She refused.
‎我还以为非要住在这里
I didn't know staying here was even an option.
‎城堡里有三个套房
There's three suites in the castle,
-杰克想住在这里...  -就住一晚
- and Jack wanted to stay here... - Just one night.
然后我们去度蜜月
before we left for the honeymoon.
‎就在明天婚宴之后
Just tomorrow. Just after the reception,
让我们跌跌撞撞地上楼
so we could just stumble upstairs.
‎但我说 "不行 ‎听了那些故事后可不行"
But I said, "No way, not after those stories."
‎等等 只是故事而已
Wait, just the stories?
‎-你没看到她  ‎-不 天啊 我没看到她
- You didn't see her? - No! God no, I didn't see her.
‎要是我看到死去的女人 ‎死去的修女在角落里哭泣
If I saw a dead woman, a dead nun, no less, crying in the corners,
‎-我们不会在这里结婚  ‎-好了 只是故事而已
- we would not be getting married here. - Okay, it's just a story.
‎这地方在40年代是个修道院 ‎有几十年的历史
This place used to be a convent for, like, a few decades in the '40s.
‎这是销售套餐的内容
It's part of the sales package.
‎他们讲这个鬼故事 ‎可能多收几百美元
They can charge a few hundred extra for the ghost story.
‎听着 我喜欢精彩的鬼故事 ‎只是不想听了去睡觉
Look, I love a good ghost story, I just don't want to sleep in one.
‎我们在爱尔兰度蜜月
We honeymooned in Ireland.
‎他们不停地告诉我们要小心
They kept telling us to look out for Seamus,
‎马房男孩谢默斯
the stable boy.
‎谢默斯
Seamus.
‎据说他的头被马踢碎了
They said his head was crushed in where a horse had kicked him.
‎鬼故事中要是有小孩 就更吓人
Ghost stories are worse when there's a kid.
‎加了点料 不是吗
Adds a little something, doesn't it?
‎我有个故事
I have a story.
‎好吧...
Well...
‎这不是我的亲身经历
it isn't really my story.
‎是我认识的一个人
It belongs to someone I knew.
‎这个故事说来话长
And it's not exactly short.
‎我们的时间似乎很充足...
Well, it seems we have time enough, and...
‎葡萄酒也够喝
wine enough.
‎干吗不讲呢
Why not?
‎那好吧
All right, then.
‎有个鬼故事
A ghost story.
‎再说一次 这个故事不是我的
Again, this story isn't mine,
‎但里面有各种各样的鬼魂
but it is full of ghosts of all sorts.
‎要是一个小孩很吓人
And if a child gives the effect,
‎让故事更惊心动魄...
another turn of the screw...
‎那么两个小孩会如何
what do you say to two?
‎这位孤单的年轻女子 ‎出于自愿当了老师
The teacher was, by choice, a solitary young woman.
‎她忐忑不安地来到伦敦 当面应聘一则广告...
Come up to London in trepidation to answer in person an advertisement...
亨利·温格雷夫爵士发布了‎这则广告
placed by one Lord Henry Wingrave
‎为他年幼的侄子和侄女
regarding his young nephew and niece,
‎招聘家庭教师
who were in need of an au pair.
‎广告上说这是全职工作
A full-time position, it said. Live-in, at that,
‎住在埃塞克斯 他古老的家族宅邸
in his old family home in Essex.
‎一个不错的好地方
A great good place,
‎在乡下与世隔绝
alone in the country.
‎是克莱顿小姐吗
Miss Clayton, is it?
‎叫我丹妮就行 你好
Call me Dani. Hi there.
‎请坐吧
Please, have a seat.
‎-你是老师吗  ‎-是的
- You're a teacher? - Yes.
‎我当过老师
Or I was.
‎教四年级
Fourth grade.
‎在美国
In the States.
‎来英国很久了吗
Been in England long?
‎大概六个月
About six months.
‎六个月 你在此期间...
Six months? During which time, you've...
‎我已经...
Well, I've...
相当钟情于伦敦
fallen quite in love with London.
‎很好
God.
‎茶还是咖啡
Tea? Coffee?
‎不了 谢谢 我还不太懂得喝茶
No, thank you. Haven't quite mastered tea yet.
‎我习惯用水壶泡茶
I'm used to it coming in a pitcher.
‎放满冰块...
Full of ice cubes...
‎还有柠檬角
and lemon wedges, and...
‎这里的茶完全不一样
Well, it's a whole different thing here.
‎是的 没错
Yes, it is.
‎你以前没有做家庭教师的经验
You've no previous experience as an au pair.
‎我...
Well, I...
‎我教孩子的经验很丰富 ‎温格雷夫先生
I've quite a bit of experience with children, Mr. Wingrave.
‎那是在教室 可这是全职住家工作
In a classroom, but this is a full-time, live-in position.
‎我知道 所以我才
I know, that's actually why
-回复广告  -孩子们很可爱
- I responded to the ad. - The children are wonderful.
‎我的侄女和侄子真的很出色
Exceptional, really, my niece and my nephew.
‎像我说的那样 出色的孩子
Exceptional children, as I said.
‎但两个孩子都很难管
But challenging, both.
‎我侄子迈尔斯 ‎提前从寄宿学校回家了
Miles, my nephew, is back home from boarding school early.
‎恐怕他比以往更需要
He needs structure,
‎约束和纪律
discipline more than ever, I fear.
‎我能问一下 他为什么被送回家吗
Well, can I ask why he was sent home?
‎-春季学期不该结束...  ‎-你要辅导他的功课
- Spring session shouldn't end... - You'd be expected to tutor him
‎让他不要成绩落后
so he doesn't fall behind.
‎你的课堂经验 ‎其实会在这方面派上用场
In that respect, your classroom experience may actually be of use.
‎我的侄女弗洛拉
The same with Flora,
‎也是如此
my niece.
‎你也要辅导她
You'd tutor her as well.
‎你的广告提到这份工作在乡间
Your ad mentioned the position was in the countryside?
‎在布莱
In Bly,
‎我家族的乡间庄园
my family's country house.
‎孩子们习惯了布莱 他们...
The children are used to Bly, they...
‎跟着父母在那里度过暑假和假日
spent summers and holidays there with their parents,
‎在父母去世前
before they passed.
‎这座庄园是个不错的好地方
It's a great good place, the manor.
‎庄园里几乎没有其他人
There are few others on the grounds.
‎厨师 园丁都住在镇上
A cook, groundskeeper. They stay in town.
‎有位管家住在家里 但孩子们...
There is a live-in housekeeper, but the children...
‎将由你负责 你一个人负责
would be your responsibility and yours alone.
‎除非有急事 否则不要给我打电话
Don't call on me unless it's an emergency.
‎我特别忙
I'm extraordinarily busy.
‎我懂了
I understand.
‎你知道
You know,
‎在我的学校 我有个更特别的任务
one of my more unique assignments at my school
是要专门照顾一些最需要帮助的孩子
was specific to some of our highest-need children,
‎-他们中又一个失去了...  ‎-有什么隐情
- one of whom had actually lost their par... - What's the catch?
‎你说什么
I'm sorry?
‎隐情 你多大了
The catch. You're what?
‎30岁
Thirty?
‎25岁
Mid-twenties?
‎我想知道...
I wonder...
‎有什么隐情
What's the catch?
‎你比应聘这类工作的大多数人都年轻
You're younger than most who'd apply for this sort of thing.
‎是什么让你这个年纪的女人
What makes a woman of your age
‎愿意放弃自己的生活 ‎去照顾别人的孩子
want to give up her life to take care of someone else's children?
‎放弃美国的生活
A life in America, at that.
‎还是全职工作
Full-time as well.
‎老实说 我觉得很奇怪
It seems odd... to me, to be frank.
‎我也觉得很奇怪
It seems odd to me too.
‎我是说广告
The listing, I mean.
‎全职工作 住在美丽的乡村庄园
A full-time position in a beautiful country manor
‎照顾两个出色的孩子
to two exceptional children.
‎但我六个月前看过你的广告
But I saw your ad six months ago.
‎我刚到伦敦的时候
When I first arrived in London.
‎此后我每个月都会看到
And I have seen it every month since.
‎我觉得这个工作很容易招到人
Seems to me an easy position to fill.
‎至少像你描述的那样
At least as you've described.
‎所以我想你说得对
So, I suppose you're right.
‎有什么隐情
What is the catch?
‎这确实是个问题
That really is the question.
‎谢谢
Thank you.
‎你好 詹姆斯
Alright, James?
‎我知道我没得到这份工作
I know I didn't get the job,
‎这没关系
and that's totally cool.
‎但这是我生平最尴尬的求职面试
But that was the most awkward job interview of my entire life.
‎我想我们该为此干杯 温格雷夫先生
So, I think we should toast to it, Mr. Wingrave.
‎还是你更喜欢喝茶
Or do you prefer it in your tea?
‎那么...
So...
‎现在你可以告诉我吗
you can tell me now, right?
‎我真的很好奇
I'm honestly so, so curious.
‎好奇什么
About what?
‎隐情
The catch.
‎-不  ‎-不 说吧
- No. - No, come on!
‎好吧...
Well...
‎我想是因为想象力
imagination, I suppose.
‎没人想要这份工作
No one wants the job.
得了吧 没人吗
Come on. No one?
‎我们有段时间招到了人
We did find someone for a while.
‎去年夏天
Last summer.
‎一位有前途的年轻姑娘
A promising young woman.
‎孩子们喜欢她
The children liked her.
‎后来她...
And then, she...
‎我想她死了
Well, I-I suppose she died.
‎恕我直言 这是她自己的错
It was her own fault, to be blunt.
‎更直白地说 这是她的选择
Her choice, to be blunter,
‎但她死在了庄园里
but she died on the grounds.
‎人们很迷信 尤其是在乡下
People are superstitious, especially in the country.
‎所以现在这变成了故事
So, now it's a story.
‎这些小孩和他们死去的父母 ‎住在那座大房子里
These small children in that huge house with their dead parents,
‎现在还有他们死去的家庭教师
and now, their dead governess.
‎哪怕他们的父母死在国外
Never mind the parents died abroad.
‎哪怕家庭教师是自杀的
Never mind the governess took her own...
‎是的 这个故事发生在招聘前
So, yes, the story precedes the job,
‎至少所有的中介都知道
at least at all the agencies.
‎现在没人想要这份工作
Now, no one wants it.
‎迷信...
Superstition...
‎想象力
imagination.
‎那你呢
What about you?
‎你有什么隐情
What was your catch?
‎我...
I...
‎不能再待在国内
couldn't be at home anymore.
‎你教过有25个孩子的班级吗
Have you ever taught a classroom of 25 kids?
‎不 恐怕我绝对没有
No, I absolutely have not, I'm afraid.
‎好吧...
Well...
‎你会喜欢他们
you take to them.
‎你爱他们
You love them.
‎即使是最坏的孩子
Even the worst ones.
‎你是这么做的
You just do.
‎你试着帮忙...
And you try to help...
‎但是孩子太多了
but there's just too many of them.
‎你的作用太小
And too little of you.
‎所以你就...
So, you just...
‎广告说有两个孩子
The ad said two children.
‎我不知道具体情况 ‎但我知道怎么管教孩子
I figure I don't know the specifics, but I know how to handle kids.
‎也许我能有所作为
Maybe I can make a difference.
‎我可以有所作为
I could. I could make a difference.
‎真的有所作为
A real difference.
‎只教两个孩子
With just two.
‎然后我注意到这是...
Then I noticed the position was...
‎全职住家工作
full-time, live-in.
‎然后我明白了 他们失去了某个人
And then it clicked. They've lost someone.
‎我能理解死亡
Now, I understand death.
‎我知道失去代表着什么
I know what loss is.
‎我要在英国多待一段时间
I'm gonna be in England a while longer.
‎其实是很长时间
Quite a while, actually.
‎我找到了工作
I got a job.
‎是啊 我的工作有试用期 ‎至少到夏天结束
Yeah, I got a trial position, at least to the end of the summer.
‎但可能持续很长...
But it could go on for quite...
‎不 我知道比我说的时间长 ‎但我找到工作了
No, I know. I know it's longer than I said, but I got a job.
‎我没有
I'm not.
‎我没有逃避什么
I'm not running from anything,
‎你这么说让我很难过
and it hurts me when you say that.
‎你知道 你这么说让我很难过
You know it hurts me when you say that.
‎无论如何...
Anyway...
‎等我到了庄园 你可以联系我
you can reach me when I get to the house.
‎等我拿到号码就打电话给你
I'll call you... when I have the number.
‎我爱你 妈妈
I love you, Mom.
‎-克莱顿小姐  ‎-是的
- Miss Clayton? - Yeah.
‎-我是欧文  ‎-嗨
- Owen. - Hi.
‎-很高兴认识你  ‎-见到你很高兴
- Pleased to meet you. - Nice to meet you.
‎-我来拿  ‎-好的 我有几个包
- Let me get... Let's get that. - Yeah. I have some bags.
‎没关系 谢谢
No worries. Thank you.
‎谢谢
Thank you.
‎不好意思 乡间小路
Sorry about that. Country roads.
‎我睡了多久
How long was I out?
‎一会儿
A while.
‎你还在过美国时间吗
Are you still on American time?
不
No.
‎我只是最近没怎么睡觉
I just haven't got much sleep lately.
‎旅馆不是很清静
Well, hostels aren't terribly restful.
‎你会发现外面要安静得多
I mean, you'll find it much quieter out here.
‎-真漂亮  ‎-是吗
- It's gorgeous. - Is it?
‎什么
What?
‎我自己也搞不懂
I can't tell anymore, personally.
‎我出生在布莱
I was born in Bly.
‎我是说小镇 不是庄园
The town, I mean, not the manor.
‎我离开了一阵子
I escaped for a bit.
‎在法国待过一段时间
Spent some time in France.
‎-什么  ‎-学习当厨师
- What? - Studying to be a chef.
‎我还以为你是司机
Yet, here I was, just thinking you were a driver.
‎不 只是偶尔开车 ‎要是亨利拜托我的话
No, no, no, only sometimes, when Henry asks me.
‎说实话 我开车的技术很烂
Frankly, I'm a rubbish driver.
‎但我的厨艺还不错
But not a bad cook, turns out.
‎你为什么回来
Why'd you come back?
‎-离开法国  ‎-家人
- From France? - Family.
‎我在这里工作可以养活自己
And this job pays the bills, while I'm here.
‎我离家也近
And it keeps me close.
‎相信我 人们会困在更糟的地方
Well, there are worse places to be stuck, believe me.
‎我其实从不喜欢布莱
I've actually never liked Bly.
‎这里的大多数人都不喜欢
The people here, most of them,
‎他们生在这里 死在这里
they're born here, they die here.
‎整个小镇就像巨大的重力井
The whole town is one big gravity well.
‎很容易陷进去
And it's easy to get stuck.
‎天啊 这是...
God, is that...
‎我说过 很可爱
Like I said, plenty to love.
‎我可以下车走完剩下的路吗
Can I get out and walk the rest of the way?
‎♪ 唱着 "哦 伤心的柳树" ♪
♪ Singing, "O willow waly" ♪
‎‎♪ 柳树也跟着我流泪 ♪
♪ By the tree that weeps with me♪
‎‎♪ 唱着 "哦 伤心的柳树" ♪
♪ Singing, "O willow waly" ♪
‎‎♪ 直到爱人回到我身旁 ♪
♪ Till my lover returns to me♪
‎这首歌真好听
What a beautiful song!
‎什么歌
What song?
‎-你刚才唱的歌  ‎-你是克莱顿小姐
- The one you were just singing. - You're Miss Clayton!
‎一定是你
You must be.
‎你真是太漂亮了
And you're so pretty.
‎我告诉过迈尔斯 你很漂亮
I told Miles you'd be pretty.
真的非常棒
How perfectly splendid!
‎你一定是弗洛拉
You must be Flora.
‎我希望我没有吓到你
I hope I didn't startle you.
‎怎么会 我在等你
Not at all. You're expected.
‎我很高兴你能来
I'm just so, so pleased you're here.
‎格罗斯太太想见你
And Mrs. Grose will want to see you.
还有迈尔斯
And Miles.
‎还有欧文和杰米
And Owen, and Jamie.
‎你知道 我见过欧文了
You know, I've met Owen.
‎你什么时候见过欧文
When did you meet Owen?
‎坐在车上的时候
On the car ride up.
‎那是什么
Now, what's that?
‎这个
This.
‎只是个蠢东西 真的
Just a silly thing, really.
‎稍等一下
Just a moment.
‎-这湖真漂亮  ‎-别这么说
- What a gorgeous lake. - You mustn't.
‎这只是个臭气熏天的老池塘
It really is just a smelly old pond.
‎你知道 里面有水蛭
And, you know, there are leeches in there.
可怕的小东西 比如吸血鼻涕虫
Horrid little things, like vampire slugs,
‎还有最恶心的甲虫
and the nastiest beetles.
‎谁要那个老池塘
Who needs that old pond, anyway?
‎世上还有那么多更好的东西
There's so much else that's so much better.
‎见到你真的非常棒
It really is perfectly splendid to meet you.
‎迈尔斯
Miles!
‎她来了 ‎她来了
She's here! She's here!
‎她比我想象的还要漂亮
And she's even prettier than I imagined.
‎这就是她
This is her!
‎嗨 迈尔斯
Hi, Miles.
‎很高兴见到你 小姐
So pleased to meet you, my lady.
真有绅士风度
Well, what the gentleman.
‎这一定是格罗斯太太
And this must be Mrs. Grose.
‎-嗨  ‎-不好意思...
- Hi! - I'm sorry...
‎天哪 我刚才走神了
Goodness, I wa... I was miles away.
‎我是丹妮
I'm Dani.
‎很高兴见到你 我是汉娜·格罗斯
It's a pleasure to meet you. Hannah Grose.
你平安到达了
Well, I see you made it in one piece.
‎-是啊  -路上还好吗
- Yeah. - Was the journey okay?
很顺利
It was perfect.
‎-太好了  ‎-是啊
- Wonderful. - Yeah.
‎是的 欧文是个不错的年轻人
Yes, that... that Owen is a fine young man.
‎很好的人
Good sort.
‎好了 我们进去吧
Right, well, let... let's find our way inside.
‎我相信克莱顿小姐一定很想看看房子
I'm sure Miss Clayton is eager to see the house.
‎-是的  -好吧 跟我来
- Yes. - Right, well, come along.
‎-现在...  ‎-你叫我丹妮就行
- Now... - You can call me Dani.
‎那怎么行
Nonsense.
‎孩子们 我们说好了 ‎你们要叫她克莱顿小姐
Children, you will call her Miss Clayton, like we agreed.
‎她第一眼看到布莱 没有感到不自在
Her first look at Bly yielded no discomfort,
‎也没有不祥的预感
no foreboding.
‎就像温格雷夫爵士描述的一样
It was exactly as Lord Wingrave had described.
‎一个不错的好地方
A great, good place.
‎这里敞开大门欢迎她到家
And it yawned open to welcome her home.
‎这是门厅
This is the foyer,
‎真的非常棒
and it's perfectly splendid.
‎-太美...  ‎-来吧
- It's beauti... - Come along!
‎这是厨房
This is the kitchen,
‎真的非常棒
and it's perfectly splendid.
‎这是欧文
And this is Owen.
‎他是厨师
He's the cook,
‎他也很棒
and he's splendid.
‎非常棒
Perfectly.
‎大家好
Hello, everyone.
‎又见面了
Again.
‎嗨
Hi!
‎嗨 弗洛拉
Hi, Flora.
‎这边请
This way.
‎这些画全是真迹
The paintings are all original,
‎也就是说 都是手绘的
which means they're painted by hand,
‎它们真的非常棒
and they're perfectly splendid.
‎这就是教室
This is the classroom.
‎这里...
It's...
‎挺无聊的
quite boring.
‎这是可爱的楼梯 但你不能在上面跑
These are the lovely stairs, but you mustn't run on them.
‎要是跌倒了 你会受伤的 ‎楼梯可不宽容
If you fall, you can injure yourself, and the stairs are not forgiving.
‎一点也不宽容 你看到了吗
Not forgiving in the least. Do you see?
‎格罗斯太太说 爬楼梯对膝盖很不好...
Mrs. Grose says they're brutal on the knees...
‎可我没什么感觉
but I don't have any issues.
‎-真气派  ‎-是啊
- Gorgeous! - It is.
‎这个地方很不错 是孩子们的天堂
A great good place. Heaven for the children.
‎但当心楼梯 爬楼梯对膝盖很不好
But mind the stairs, they're brutal on the knees.
‎这是我们父母从前住的地方
And this is where our parents used to live.
‎我们不再去了
We don't go in there anymore.
我们不再去了 全遮起来了
We don't go in there anymore. It's all covered up.
‎恐怕这个房间现在锁上了
This room is closed at the moment.
‎遮起来了 但是全在下面
And covered up. But underneath it all,
‎一切真的非常棒
it's all just perfectly splendid.
‎我们让克莱顿小姐梳洗一下
Let's leave Miss Clayton to freshen up.
‎当然
Of course.
‎但我们必须带她参观雕像花园
But then we must show her the statue garden.
她早晚会看到的 弗洛拉
She'll see it all eventually, Flora.
‎等你安顿好了 我们再来看你
We'll see you after you've settled.
‎等你安顿好了 我们带你看其他地方
And once you have, we'll have to show you the rest.
‎弗洛拉
Flora!
‎来了
Coming.
‎不好意思 我可以进来吗
I'm sorry. May I come in?
‎是的 当然
Yes. Of course.
‎也许从现在开始学会敲门
Perhaps knock from now on.
‎当然
Of course.
‎我只想说 你来了让我们很开心
I just wanted to say how happy we all are that you're here.
‎给你这个
And to give you this.
‎不算什么 我知道
Not much, I know.
‎只是件小东西 让你感到宾至如归
Just a little something to make you feel more welcome.
‎谢谢
Thank you.
‎很漂亮
It's very pretty.
‎我先把这里收拾完 等会见好吗
I'm just gonna finish up here and see you in a few minutes, okay?
‎当然了
Of course.
‎谢谢
Thank you.
我希望你别介意
I hope it's all right.
‎我还没弄明白茶 所以...
I haven't quite figured out tea yet, so...
‎没事 亲爱的
It's fine, dear.
‎晚餐准备好了
Dinner is served.
‎给你 孩子  ‎
There you go, mate.
-谢谢  -欧文做的晚餐最好吃
- Thank you. - Owen makes the best dinners.
‎他给我做过一次 ‎通心粉和奶酪三明治
He made me a macaroni-and-cheese sandwich once,
‎很好吃
which was divine.
‎是什么让你这样的美国年轻人来到英国
So, what brings a young American like you to England?
而且偏偏来到布莱
And Bly of all places.
‎你知道 只是想见识世界
You know, just wanted to see the world.
‎目前为止 你觉得怎么样
And what do you think of it so far?
‎-布莱 还是世界  ‎-我想去澳大利亚
- Bly? Or the world? - I want to go to Australia.
‎或者佛罗里达 跟我的名字很像
Or Florida, because it's almost my name.
‎没错
That's right.
‎-这里真是太美了  ‎-是啊
- It's just so gorgeous here. - Yeah.
‎我一直这么说 但想不出别的词
I know I keep saying that, but there's no other word.
‎-我倒能想出几个  ‎-闭嘴吧 欧文
- I could think of a few others. - Hush now, Owen.
‎-他喜欢捉弄我  ‎-她喜欢被捉弄
- He likes to wind me up. - She likes being wound up.
‎你不跟我们一起吃吗
Aren't you joining us?
‎今晚不行 亲爱的 我得回家看我妈妈
Not tonight, sweetheart. I've got to go home to my mom.
‎令人失望
Disappointing.
‎你的口气跟她一模一样
You sound just like her.
‎她感觉好些了吗
Is she feeling better?
‎好多了
Much.
‎我觉得每天都越来越好
Better every day, I reckon.
‎好了
All right.
‎晚安 你这位可爱的小姐
Good night, you lovely young lady.
‎也祝你晚安 弗洛拉
And good night to you, too, Flora.
‎老天保佑我 这家伙
Heaven help me, this man.
‎好好享用
Enjoy.
‎他和他母亲一起生活
So, he lives with his mother?
‎更像是为她而活着
Lives for her, more like.
‎这就是他从巴黎回来的原因
That's why he came back from Paris.
‎她病了 我听说病得很重
She took ill. Quite ill, I've heard.
‎-真遗憾  ‎-是啊
- I'm sorry. - Yeah.
‎他说她在好转
He said she's getting better.
‎每天都越来越好
Yeah, better every day.
‎他是这么说 可最近他走得越来越早
He says that, but he leaves earlier and earlier these days.
‎他过去每晚都留下来吃晚饭
He used to stay every night for supper.
‎也许她感觉很好 可以吃东西了
Maybe she feels well enough to eat,
‎所以他必须及时回家给她做饭
so he has to get home in time to cook for her.
‎我相信你说得对 亲爱的
I'm sure you're right, sweetheart.
‎怎么 你不吃吗
What? You're not gonna eat?
是的
Well, yeah.
‎-我等会儿吃  ‎-好的
- I'll have it later. - Okay.
‎我会指点你的
I'll give you some pointers.
‎谢谢
Thank you.
‎我希望看起来像个矮人
I wish to look like a gnome.
‎泡沫矮人
A bubble gnome.
‎你肯定能行
Well, you're sure getting there.
‎什么
What?
‎这真的很傻 不是吗
It really is very silly, isn't it?
‎是的 你是个很傻的女孩
Yes, you're a very silly girl.
‎你从哪里弄到的
Where did you get that?
‎-什么  ‎-那个蝴蝶发夹
- What? - The butterfly clip.
‎迈尔斯送给我的
Miles gave it to me.
‎他不该那么做
He shouldn't have done that.
‎为什么不行
Why not?
‎因为那不是你的东西
Because it doesn't belong to you.
‎那是谁的东西
Who does it belong to?
‎-杰塞尔小姐  ‎-那是谁
- Miss Jessel. - Who's that?
‎另一个人
The other one.
‎-你的前任  ‎-我...
- Before you. - I'm...
‎我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
‎我...
I...
‎我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
‎我错了 其实没什么
I was wrong. It's actually fine.
‎我现在能出来了吗
Can I get out now?
‎我可以玩我的娃娃吗
Can I play with my dolls?
‎可以 15分钟 好吗
Yeah. Fifteen minutes, okay?
我去过你能想到的各种学校
You know, I've gone to every kind of school you can think of.
‎真的
Have you?
‎我还上过寄宿学校 像你一样
Even a boarding school once, like you.
‎我知道这有多难
I know how hard it can be.
‎没那么糟糕
It's not so bad.
‎好吧...
Well...
‎你现在回家了 不是吗
you're home now, aren't you?
‎听着 你想跟我说什么都可以
Look, you can talk to me about whatever you'd like.
‎学校的事
About school.
‎学校发生的任何事
Anything that happened there.
‎我保证 我都听说了
I promise, I've heard it all.
‎你真是太好了
It's very kind of you.
‎晚安 丹妮
Good night, Dani.
‎晚安
Good night.
‎对了 格罗斯太太似乎认为 ‎你应该叫我克莱顿小姐
You know, Mrs. Grose seems to think you should call me Miss Clayton.
‎你不喜欢吗
Didn't you like it?
‎你说什么
I'm sorry?
‎蝴蝶发夹
The butterfly.
‎我...
I...
‎我觉得 ‎弗洛拉...
You know, Flora...
有点不高兴
was a little upset, I think.
‎她总是有点不高兴
She's always a little upset.
‎不管她承不承认
Whether she admits it or not.
‎但她很高兴你来了
But she's so, so glad you're here.
‎我也是
And so am I.
‎谢谢你让我感到宾至如归
Well, thank you for making me feel so welcome.
‎睡觉了
Bedtime!
‎我刚收拾好
And I'm finished.
‎时间刚好
Perfect timing.
‎那是我吗
Is that me?
‎才不是 傻子 你就是你
Why, no, silly. You're you.
‎这只是个娃娃
It's just a dolly.
‎说得对
Touché.
‎这些都是谁
Who are all these?
‎怎么 他们当然都是娃娃
Why, they're dolls, of course.
‎小姐 你有很多娃娃
You, miss, have a lot of dolls,
‎我们要学会在睡觉前
and we're going to learn
‎把娃娃都收起来 好吗
how to pick them all up before we go to sleep, okay?
‎把她放回去
Put her back.
‎她就待在...
She stays...
‎那里
there.
‎你们都盖好被子
And you're all tucked in.
‎现在该睡觉了
And it's time for bed.
‎你来了真是太好了
It's just lovely that you're here.
‎谢谢你 弗洛拉
Thank you, Flora.
‎但你得答应我一件事
But you have to promise me something.
‎当然
Of course.
‎你得答应我
You have to promise me
‎你会待在你的房间
that you'll stay in your room.
‎晚上不要离开你的房间
Don't leave your room at night.
‎在床上待到天亮
Stay in your bed until morning.
‎我想我不能答应
I don't think I can promise that.
‎但对你和你哥哥来说 ‎这肯定是好规矩...
But it's certainly a good rule for you and your brother...
‎但你必须答应
But you must.
‎好吧
Okay.
‎至少今天晚上
At least for tonight.
‎现在去睡吧
Now get some sleep.
‎这天夜里 家庭教师辗转难眠
The night found the au pair restless.
‎像弗洛拉说的那样
It was as Flora had said.
‎房间在晚上变大了
The rooms were larger at night,
‎仿佛太阳落山的时候
as though the house itself had inhaled deeply
‎这座房子深吸了一口气
as the sun disappeared,
‎不断扩大 屏住呼吸等待早晨的到来
expanding as it held its breath for the morning.
‎这种扩张感不仅存在于室内
That sense of expansion wasn't only indoors, either.
‎向外望去 她发现露台和整个庄园
Gazing out, she found that the terrace and the whole place,
‎草坪和外面的花园
the lawn and the garden beyond it,
‎她能看到的地方都空无一人
and all she could see of the park, were empty,
‎空空荡荡
with a great emptiness.
‎这种空旷让人想一探究竟
An emptiness that called out to be explored.
‎挺好喝的啊
Tastes good to me.
‎今天天气真好
What a beautiful day.
‎我发誓 我永远不会厌倦这个地方
Well, I'll never get tired of this place, I swear.
‎怎么了
What's the matter?
‎我很生你的气
I'm very cross with you.
‎克莱顿小姐
Miss Clayton!
‎过来看看我发现了什么
Come see what I found!
‎你昨晚离开了房间 ‎可你答应不会的
You left your room last night even though you promised you wouldn't.
‎-克莱顿小姐  ‎-你怎么知道的
- Miss Clayton! - How do you know that?
‎你必须待在你的房间里
You've got to stay in your room.
‎快来看
Come and see!
‎-怎么了  ‎-这样她就看不到你
- Why? - So she doesn't see you.
‎谁
Who?
‎那位女士
The lady.
‎什么女士
What lady?
‎-湖中的女士  ‎-弗洛拉
- The lady in the lake. - Flora.
‎弗洛拉 你看
Flora, look.
‎克莱顿小姐...
Miss Clayton...
‎看
Look!
‎听着 我已经当了九年老师 迈尔斯
Look, I've been a teacher for nine years, Miles.
‎跟你的年龄差不多大
That's almost your whole life.
‎这些年
In all that time,
很多孩子想尽办法吓唬我
a lot of kids have tried to scare me in a lot of different ways,
‎你知道我学到了什么吗
and you know what I learned?
‎我比人们想的要勇敢得多
I'm a lot braver than people think.
‎也包括我
Including me.
‎我没想吓唬你 克莱顿小姐
I wasn't trying to scare you, Miss Clayton.
‎我知道你不会害怕
I knew you wouldn't be frightened.
‎是吗
Did you?
‎当然 我一看就知道你是这样的人
Of course. I knew that about you right away.
‎你在学校经常做这种事吗
Is that something you used to do at school?
‎搞恶作剧
Play pranks?
‎捣蛋
Tricks.
‎我从来不太明白捣蛋的意思
I never quite saw the point of tricks.
‎你叔叔跟我说过一些你在学校的问题
Your uncle told me a little bit about your problems at school.
‎你和我叔叔谈过了
You spoke with my uncle?
‎当然 他雇了我
Well, of course. He hired me.
‎他问起我们了吗
Did he ask about us?
‎他说的全是你们两个
All he did was talk about you two.
‎他很想你们两个
He misses you both.
‎非常想
Very much.
‎不 他不想
No, he doesn't.
‎他当然想
Of course he does.
‎我们要不要给他打电话问问
Shall we give him a ring and ask?
‎家庭教师为男孩的痛苦而心痛
The au pair's heart ached for the boy's pain.
‎但就像布莱的天气一样
But, like the very weather at Bly,
他的情绪变化很快
his moods proved quick to change.
‎就像太阳 云和雨会毫无预兆地出现
As sun, clouds, and rain would appear without hint or warning,
‎孩子们的情绪也是如此
so, too, did the children's moods.
‎仿佛时间和自然...
As though time and nature held...
‎专为他们制定了...
secret laws...
‎秘密法则
just for them.
‎她来了
There she is.
‎他们扔下我跑了
They got away from me.
‎不 我去接电话 你坐吧
No, I'll get it. You have a seat.
‎放松点
Relax.
‎如果可以的话
If that's even possible.
‎你好
Hello?
‎午餐吃什么
What's for lunch?
‎-香肠配土豆泥  ‎-喂
- Bangers and mash. - Hello?
‎喂
Hello?
‎弗洛拉 别这样
Flora, don't.
‎-谁打来的  ‎-不知道 电话挂了
- Who was it? - Don't know. They hung up.
‎-又来了  ‎-又一个
- Again? - Another one?
‎我们接过几个恶作剧电话
We've had some, prank calls.
‎-可能是打错了  ‎-谢谢
- Probably just a wrong number. - Thank you.
‎不客气
You're welcome.
‎克莱顿小姐
Miss Clayton.
‎谢谢
Thank you.
‎园丁没有向新来的家庭教师
The gardener did not even introduce herself
‎做自我介绍
to the new au pair.
‎她几乎不认识她
She barely acknowledged her at all.
‎只是把她当做一直在那里的人
Simply treated her as if she'd always been there.
‎房间里其他人还以为 ‎她们已经见过了
The others in the room just assumed they'd already met,
‎如果她没说谎
which, if she were honest,
‎这就是家庭教师第一次看到这个年轻女人的感觉
was how the au pair felt when she first saw the young woman.
‎是谁决定喂养这些小精怪的
So, who decided it was a good idea to feed these wee gremlins?
‎我们不是小精怪
We're not gremlins!
‎我们是乖孩子
We're very good children.
‎是这样吗
Is that right?
‎我可不确定
See, I'm not so sure.
‎欧文 你觉得呢
Owen, what do you think?
‎很难说
It's hard to say.
‎我得给他们浇点水才能确定
I'm gonna have to get water on them to be sure.
‎像这样吗
Like this?
‎给你
There you go.
‎-给你 亲爱的  ‎-你太好了 谢谢
- There you go, dear. - You're a star. Thank you.
‎今天有没有人...
Was there somebody...
‎在庄园里干活
working on the grounds today?
‎也许是修理工什么的
Maybe a repairman or something?
‎不 我想没有
No, I don't believe so.
‎因为我进来的时候
'Cause I saw a guy,
‎看见有人在护墙上
on the parapet, on my way in.
‎在护墙上
On the parapet?
‎是啊
Yeah.
‎-无法想象  ‎-我没上去过
- Can't imagine. - I've not been up there.
怎么会呢
Well, why would you?
你确定看到上面有人吗
Are you sure you saw someone up there?
‎绝对没错 我挥手了 他没有回应
Absolutely. I waved, he didn't wave back.
‎偶尔会有闲逛的人
Well, we do get ramblers sometimes.
‎有人想看看花园
People that wanna have a look at the gardens.
‎他们随意走动 但如果有人爬上护墙...
They take liberties, but if one made it onto the parapet...
‎他们上不去 不穿过房子是上不去的
They can't get up there, not without going through the house.
‎只有穿过老楼才能上去
The only way up there is through the old wing.
‎我们不能去哪里
And where don't we go?
‎老楼
The old wing.
‎这肯定是你的幻觉 亲爱的
You must have imagined it, dear.
‎-你不吃饭吗  ‎-不 我吃过了
- You're not gonna eat anything? - No, I already ate.
‎只是来陪你们
Just here for the company.
‎你一定要尝尝这个
You must try this.
‎弗洛拉 别这样
Flora, don't.
‎你找到那个人了
Did you... Did you find anyone?
‎没有
No.
‎我没找到
I didn't.
‎但是...
But...
‎我确实找到了...
I did find some...
‎对不起 我打扰你了吗
I'm sorry. Am I interrupting you?
‎不 一点也没有
No. No, not at all.
‎你发现了什么
What did you find?
‎是弗洛拉
It's Flora.
‎-弗洛拉...  ‎-我见过几个这样的孩子
- Flora, Flora... - I've seen a few of these.
‎你不能这样评判他们
Well, you can't judge them.
‎尤其是他们经历了这些事
Not after what they've been through.
‎温格雷夫先生肯定跟你说过他们的父母
Mr. Wingrave told you about their parents, I'm sure.
‎只说他们过世了
Only that they passed.
‎两年前的这个时候
Two years ago, now.
‎迈尔斯只有八岁 弗洛拉六岁
Miles was only eight. Flora, six.
‎两个孩子真够倒霉的
And that's enough bad luck for two children to bear,
‎可是想到...
but then to think...
‎后来发生的事情
what came after.
‎你的前任
Your... your predecessor.
‎-杰塞尔小姐  ‎-是的
- Miss Jessel? - Yeah.
‎丽贝卡
Rebecca.
‎天啊...
God...
‎丽贝卡 可怜的丽贝卡
Rebecca. Poor Rebecca.
‎她是...
She was...
‎她是个聪明的年轻人
She was a bright young thing.
‎她雄心勃勃 聪慧过人
She was ambitious, intelligent.
‎心地善良
Kind of heart.
‎但是...
But...
‎有个男人
there was a man.
‎真的只有这种事能毁掉这样的女人
Which really is the only thing that can bring down a woman like that.
‎世间所有的恶行披着优雅的外衣
All the world's vices in disguise of its graces.
‎总之 他的事说得越少越好
Anyway, the less said about him, the better.
‎你知道他逃跑了吗
You know he skipped town?
‎卷走了亨利的一大笔钱 ‎还有那可怜姑娘的心
With a tidy sum of Henry's money and the poor thing's heart.
‎偷了很多东西 手脚不干净
Stole a lot, that one. Sticky fingers.
‎在逃走前几天还见过她
And to see her in the days leading up to it.
‎多么伤心
So broken.
‎多么空虚
So empty.
‎在她投入湖中之前 她早就走了
She was gone long before she waded into that lake.
‎弗洛拉发现了她
Flora found her.
‎杰米发现了弗洛拉
And Jamie found Flora.
‎听她说...
To hear her tell it...
‎丽贝卡的尸体在水里
Rebecca's body in that water.
‎脸朝下
Face down.
‎小弗洛拉只是...
And little Flora just...
‎一动不动...
stone-still...
‎瞪着眼睛
staring.
‎我...
And I...
‎从前我听到孩子们在房子里跑来跑去...
To think I used to cringe when I heard the children...
‎尖叫吵闹的时候 我感到很尴尬
running through the house, screaming and kicking up a fuss.
‎但在杰塞尔小姐去世后的几周里...
But in the weeks after Miss Jessel there...
‎寂静从未让人感到如此可怕
Silence, it never felt so terrible.
‎现在...
And now...
‎现在我听到他们...
Now, when I hear them...
‎哭闹...
cry, or...
‎大吼大叫...
scream, or yell...
‎天啊 这是世界上最动听的声音
God, it's the most beautiful sound in the world.
‎-我很抱歉  ‎-不
- I'm so sorry. - No.
‎-没关系  ‎-天啊 看看我
- It's all right. - God, look at me.
‎这是个护身符
It's a talisman.
‎弗洛拉的小游戏 ‎保佑我们所有人的安全
A tiny game of Flora's to keep us all safe.
‎我们
Us.
‎天啊 那些孩子
God. My God, these children.
‎我想 他们都在用自己的方式 ‎努力适应
Both of them trying in their own way, I think.
‎你知道 我该回去了
You know, I should head back.
‎欧文和杰米今晚要离开
Owen and Jamie will be leaving for the evening.
‎要是你愿意的话 ‎我很高兴在睡前照看孩子们
But I'm happy to watch the children before bed if you'd like a moment.
‎这些蜡烛是为谁点的
What are the candles for?
‎死人
The dead.
‎我年龄越大 死人就越多 ‎超乎我的想象
There's more of them than I'd like, the older I get.
‎对不起
I'm sorry.
‎天哪 没必要
God, no need.
‎我从前是个幸福的女人 现在也是
I have been, and I remain, a very happy woman.
‎晚上好 克莱顿小姐
Good evening, Miss Clayton.
‎该睡觉了
Time for bed.
‎是吗
Is it?
‎我不想睡觉
I shouldn't think so.
‎别玩游戏了 迈尔斯
No more games, Miles.
‎你喜欢游戏吗 丹妮
Do you like games, Dani?
‎不是在睡觉的时候
Not at bedtime.
‎现在是玩游戏最好的时间 真的
It's the best time for games, really.
‎别搞怪了 迈尔斯
Stop being weird, Miles!
‎他有时真的很奇怪
He's so weird sometimes.
‎还有你...
And you...
‎亲爱的
sweet thing.
‎想象力
Imagination.
‎我喜欢...
I love...
‎你的想象力
your imagination.
‎这房子里的每个人都很幸运...
And everyone in this house is so lucky...
‎你用想象力来保佑我们的安全
that you're using yours to keep us safe.
‎只是答应我...
Just promise me...
‎如果你要保佑我们所有人的安全
that when you're keeping us all safe,
‎首先要保证你自己的安全
that you keep yourself safe first.
‎不要到护墙上
And no going on the parapet.
‎好的
Okay.
‎你还真是 你知道吗
You really are, you know?
‎我怎么了
I'm what?
‎真的非常棒
Perfectly splendid.
‎晚安 小可爱
Good night, sweet girl.
‎对不起
I'm sorry!
‎你知道 你要确保把这些东西收好
You know, you need to make sure that you pick these up.
‎我不想弄坏...
I would hate to break...
‎你今晚想把她放在哪里
Where would you like her tonight?
‎在屋子里 还是在梳妆台下面
In the house or under the dresser?
‎克莱顿小姐
Miss Clayton?
‎我正要给你掖被子
I was just about to tuck you in.
‎弗洛拉的衣帽间里有一台电扇
There's an electric fan in Flora's cupboard.
‎没有电扇 我恐怕睡不着觉
I cannot sleep without it, I'm afraid.
‎对了
That... that's right.
‎我的衣帽间
My cupboard.
‎你能帮我拿过来吗 真不好意思
Would you fetch it for me? I'm awfully sorry.
‎没问题
Sure thing.
‎好了...
Well...
‎给你
here you go.
‎她今晚可以和你睡
She can sleep with you tonight.
‎好的 我们来看看
Okay, let's look.
‎-我没看到  -肯定在衣服下面
- I don't see it! - It must be under some clothes.
‎好的
Okay.
‎孩子们
Guys.
‎我说别闹了
I said no games.
‎打开
Open up!
‎打开门
Open the door!
‎开门
Open it!
‎我在使劲
I'm trying!
‎迈尔斯
Miles!
‎我在使劲
I'm trying!
‎弗洛拉
Flora!
‎卡住了 我们真的在使劲
It's stuck. We're really trying!
‎好吧 这不好笑
Okay, it's not... it's not funny.
‎打开门
Open the door.
‎我们得找到钥匙 真的卡住了
We'll have to find the key. It really is stuck.
‎-我们很抱歉  ‎-钥匙在锁里 弗洛拉
- We're very sorry! - The key is in the lock, Flora.
‎转动钥匙
Turn the key.
‎不行 我们找不到钥匙
It's not! We can't find it!
‎我是说真的
I'm being serious.
‎打开门
Open the door!
‎迈尔斯
Miles!
‎弗洛拉
Flora?
‎打开门
Open the door!
打开门
‎不
No!
‎打开门
Open the door!
‎孩子们
Guys!
‎让我出去
Let me out!
‎让我出去 让我出去
Let me out! Let me out!
Let me out! Let me out!
‎很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
‎我们非常抱歉
We're dreadfully sorry.
‎睡觉
Bed!
‎那是个意外
It was an accident.
‎睡觉
Bed!
‎马上
Now!
‎对不起
I am sorry.
‎-请别生气  ‎-我们明早再谈这件事
- Please, don't be cross. - We'll talk about it in the morning.
‎你们去外面了吗
Were you outside?